Mss.B.Ow2 Mss.B.Ow2
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence
  - Letter to Sir William Hooker, Oct. 23, 1843; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    See: (Sir Richard Owen papers.)
    Hooker, William Jackson, Sir, 1785-1865 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to "Dear Barlow", Nov. 13, 1843; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to William White Cooper, Hanover Square, June 8, 1844; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 59.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
    Cooper, William White -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Mrs. Poyser, Harrogate, Oct. 18, 1844; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Southampton, A.L.S. 4p.,add. (see R.Owen Letters to various persons, no. 10.) Friendly letter. Refers to Cooper. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to J[ohn] Ella, Dec. 17, 1844; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Owen papers.) Cannot join the Musical Union, although music is his favorite amusement. Formerly B Ow2.16
  - Letter to "My dear Edwards", March 24, 1845; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Owen papers.) Read his report on the venous system of the mollusks. Sorry he is ill. Formerly B Ow2.19
  - Letter to [Henri Milne-] Edwards, March 25, 1845; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Owen papers Forwards writing on medicine. Friendly letter. Formerly B Ow2.8
    Milne-Edwards, H., (Henri), 1800-1885 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Mr. Dixon, Nov. 29, 1845; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Rob[er]t Dunn, Feb. 26, 1847; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Richard Owen], August 16, 1847
  - Letter to Prof. Owen, Nov. 11, 1847; Chadwick, Edwin, Sir, 1800-1890.
  - Letter to [Richard] Owen, Dec. 13, 1847; Buckland, William, 1784-1856
  - Letters to Henri Milne-Edwards, 1845, 1880; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 5 items. Various sizes. Table of contents available. Formerly B Ow2.8
  - Letter to William White Cooper, Jan. 11, 1848; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. (see R.Owen. Letters to Various persons, no. 11.) Letter of sympathy. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to "My dear B.", Feb. 25, 1848; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to ----., March 22, 1848; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Milne-Edwards, July 10, 1848; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Lindley, Sept. 1, 1848; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "My dear Cooper", Oct. 12, 1848; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Richard] Owen, Nov. 22, 1848; Taylor, John, 1781-1864
  - Letter to ----, Dec. 28, 1848; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir Richard Owen. Papers.) Identifies fossils from Palermo. Formerly B Ow2.5
  - Letter to Mrs. C. Southwood Hill, Jan. 3, 1849; Owen, Richard, 1810-1890
  - Letter to [Philip Pearsall] Carpenter, April 6, 1849; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p.,end. (see Sir R.Owen Papers. Letters to various persons, no. 2.) Friendly letter. Formerly B Ow2.2
    Carpenter, Philip Pearsall, 1819-1877 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to [Richard] Owen, June 15, 1849; Lyell, Charles, Sir, 1797-1875
  - Letter to Mr. Murray, July 7, 1849; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "Dear Sir;", September 11, [1849]; 7 x 4 1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Stoke on Trent, ALS 1p. Asks that his paper "On the Anatomy of Lucernaria, with the characters of a species new to the British Coasts, "be read at the meeting [of the British Assoc.], in the Zoological Section on Thursday the 13th.
    See: (Report of the Brit.Assoc., vol. 19, p. 78, 1849. Trans. of the Sections.)
  - Letter to [Richard] Owen, Sept. 18, 1849; 7 x 4 3/8; Clark, James, Sir, 1788-1870
    ALS 2p.(part of p.2 missing) Makes arrangements for visit to Lord John Russell. Mentions Dr. [Edwin] Lankester.
  - Journal of Tour to North, Sept. 11, 23, 1849; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.D. 1p. (see R.Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 12.) Made lectures on natural history. On same sheet as letter from Owen to Sir W.W. Cooper; Sept. 29, 1849. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to William White Cooper, Sept. 29, 1849; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 4p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 12.) Death of Dixon. Friendly letter. On same sheet is extract of R. Owen Journal of Tour to North, Sept. 11-23, 1849. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to [Richard] Owen, [1849]; Lyell, Charles, Sir, 1797-1875
  - Letter to Mrs. Roebuck, Jan. 3, 1850; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Richard] Owen, March 13, 1850; Acland, Henry W., (Henry Wentworth), 1815-1900
  - Letter to Professor Jameson, August 3, 1850; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Sir John [Lubbock], Oct. 8, 1850; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. (see R.Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 13.) Accepts invitation. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to Tho[ma]s [Charles] Waterton, Oct. 18, 1850; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 4p., enclosure wanting. Owen, on behalf of the commissioners of the Great Exhibition, requests Waterton to send some of his choice specimens of birds, insects, quadrupeds and Crustacea as examples of the improvements made in the art of tax idermy. Mentions Mrs. Owen.
  - Letter to William White Cooper, Dec. 2, 1850; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. (see R.Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 14.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to Sir John Lubbock, Jan. 8, 1851; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 41.) Accepts invitation for dinner. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to Sir Philip [Egerton], Jan. 31, 1851; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Grey-Egerton, Philip de Malpas, Sir, 10th bart., 1806-1881 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to [Richard] Owen, May 8, 1851; 6 x 3 3/4; Clark, James, Sir, 1788-1870
    Brook Street, ALS 1p. Invitation to dinner on Saturday the 17th at a quarter to seven o'clock.
  - Letter to ----, June 23, [1851?]; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir R.Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 3.) Concerning Brandt. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to "My dear Lance", July 29, 1851; 7x41/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. "...had hoped to have been able to have called for [his umbrella] and asked how you all are after your agreeable & gay entertainment."
    See: (Owen papers.)
  - Letter to [J. A. Ransome], Aug. 18, 1851; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 3p. Looks forward to visiting with them. His family will use the house by the sea. Refers to Quekett.
  - Letter to George Ransome, Sept. 4, 1851; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see R.Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 15.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
    Ransome, George -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Prof. Owen, Oct. 15, 1851; Carpenter, William Benjamin, 1813-1885
  - Letter to [Richard] Owen, Oct. 19, 1851; Sedgwick, Adam, 1785-1873
  - Letter to [Richard] Owen, Jan. 10, 1852; 6 x 3 7/8; Clark, James, Sir, 1788-1870
    ALS 3p. Concerns Certificate sent by Dr. Davy. Dr. [Charles Edward?] Blair would have another chance of election to the Royal Society; Owen has personal knowledge of him.
  - Letter to R[ichard] H[engist] Horne, Feb. 4, 1852; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Horne, R. H., (Richard H.), 1802-1884 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to ----., May 20, 1852; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Richard] H[engist] Horne, May 20, 1852; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "My dear Friend", May 23, 1852; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [George William] Manby, May 26, 1852; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Owen papers.) Thanks for the theater performance. Comments on the theater. Formerly B Ow2.15
    Manby, George William, 1765-1854 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Prof. Owen, July 6, 1852; White, Adam, 1817-1879
    Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Prof. Owen, Dec. 1, 1852; Longman, William
  - Letter to "Dear Sir;", Dec. 21, 1852; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Owen papers) Thanks for the Christmas present. Tells how much he appreciates it. Formerly B Ow2.20
  - Letter to [Richard] Owen, Jan. 16, 1853; Hooker, William Jackson, Sir, 1785-1865
  - Letter to Sir John [Lubbock], June 24, 1853; 4x3-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Sheen Gate, A.L.S. 2p. (see R.Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 16.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to G. H. Lewis, August 9, 1853; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Richard Owen], August 29, 1853; Broderip, William John, 1789-1859
  - Letter to Prof. Owen, Dec. 11, 1853; Playfair, Lyon Playfair, Baron, 1818-1898
  - Letter to Mr. Thompson, May 18, 1854; 7x4½; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    London, A.L.S. 1p. Asks Thompson to show the bearer of the letter, who "takes great interest in Natural Hitory,...the activity of the great Serpents, Which is sometimes remarkable, after sunset, in, sultry weather".
    See: (Owen Papers.)
  - Letter to Mrs. H. Parker, June 2, 1854; 4-1/2x3; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.in 3d P. 4p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 17.) Thanks for shells. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to [Richard Owen], June 8, 1854; 6 x 3 7/8; Clark, James, Sir, 1788-1870
    Brook Street, ALS 1p. Asks Owen to have some one point out the more important parts of the [British Museum to Dr. Chelluti (?) of Malta.
  - Letter to [Richard] Owen, Aug. 5, [18]54; 6 7/8 x 4 1/2; Clark, James, Sir, 1788-1870
    Brook Street, ALS 2p. Saw Dr. Khan when he visited museum; shall be glad to have Khan call on him any morning. Thinks part of Khan's museum ought to be open to the public.
  - Letter to ----., Sept. 29, 1854; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Richard Owen], Oct. 4, 1854; Gibson, John
  - Letter to Prof. Owen, Oct. 10, 1854; Thomson, W.
  - Letter to [Richard Owen], Oct. 13, 1854; Thomson, W.
  - Letter to ----., Nov. 14, 1854; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Samuel H. Beccles, Brighton, April 12, 1855; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    London, A.L.S. 3p. (see Owen papers.) Geological study and fossil remains. Formerly B Ow2.11
  - Letter to William White Cooper, June 30, 1855; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. (see R.Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 18.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to [E. L.] Layard, Oct. 1, 1855; 10x7-3/4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    London, A.L.S. 4p. (see Owen papers.) Comments on Austin Layard. Concerning zoological specimens for museums. Natural history discussions. Friendly letter. Formerly B Ow2.12
  - Letter to ----, Nov. 24, 1855; 7" x 4 1/2"; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    London, A.L.S. 1p. Acknowledges notification of the meeting of the Branch society.
  - Letter to [William] Sharpey, London, 29 Nov., 1855; 7 x 4 1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    ALS 2p. env. Sends instructions on how to reach cottage by taking train to Mortlake.
  - Letter to William White Cooper, Dec. 16, 1855; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 3p. (see R.Owen. Letters to various persons. no. 19.) Friendly letter. Refers to Dickens. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to [Richard Owen], Jan. 7, 1856; Broderip, William John, 1789-1859
  - Letter to [Edward] Jesse, Feb. 5, 1856; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    London, A.L.S. 2p. (see R.Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 21.) Friendly letter. Fishes. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to "My dear Pickersgill", Feb. 23, 1856; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "Dear Warren", April 22, 1856; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "My dear Warren", June 27, 1856; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Edwin] Lankester, Sept. 18, 1856; 7x4½; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. Informs Lankester of Prince Albert's contribution to the geographical and zoological researches of Ida Pfeiffer. Mentions the British Association.
  - Letter to Dr. [Thomas] Horsfield, Sept. 23, [1856?]; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for his gift of skeletons of animals to Royal College of Surgeons.
    See: (Richard Owen Papers.)
  - Letter to [Henri] Milne-Edwards, Oct. 5, 1856; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Owen papers.) Announces his appointment as professor of comparative anatomy and paleontology at the British museum. Formerly B Ow2.8
  - Letter to "My dear Sir", October 20, 1856; 7x4½; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 4p. Refers to Mrs. Cox's investigations of beds of native fossil manure forming part of the Red Crag deposits of Suffolk and Essex. Mentions British Association; John Hunter; Royal College of Surgeons; and Mr. Liddell
  - Letter to "Dear Linton", Nov. 27, 1856; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Synopsis of a course of lectures... by Professor Owen, F.R.S., February 27 - April 3, 1857; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Messrs. Dalgrel, Brothers, June 17, 1857; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    British Museum, A.L.S. 2p. (see R.Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 23.) Concerning a publication. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to "My dear Madam" [Duchess of Argyle?], June 29, 1857; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Miss Fisher, July 1, 1857; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Richard] Owen, July 17, 1857; 6 1/8 x 3 7/8; Clark, James, Sir, 1788-1870
    ALS 2p. Makes no apology for sending Dr. [John?] Davy's note; would like more information on it. "Would be great triumph if one could people the rivers of one quarter of the world with fish from another."
  - Letter to "My dear Lord" [Thomas Spring-Rice? Baron, Monteagle of Brandon], March 26, 1858; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 3p.and end. (see Sir R.Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 4.) Friendly letter. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to Prof. Owen, April 19, 1858; Warren, Samuel
  - Letter to [Henri] Milne-Edwards, June 10, 1858; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Ed[ward] Baines, Sept. 27, 1858; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Dr. Sharpey, Dec. 8, 1858; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Richard Owen papers.) Prepares answer for the British Association for the Advancement of Science to question to the Prince Consort's question, and refers to Sir John Herschel and Sir Benjamin Brody. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to [Richard Owen], Dec. 30, 1858; Sabine, Edward, Sir, 1788-1883
  - Letter to Hepworth Dixon, Jan. 12, 1859; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    British Museum, A.L.S. 1p. (see R.Owen. Letters to Various persons, no. 25.) Friendly letter. Sends report of his lecture on the gorilla. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to ----., March 11, 1859; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Addressed envelope to Jabez Hogg, [April 11, 1859]; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to William White Cooper, April 16, 1859; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 1p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 26.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to Mr. Parker, June 18, 1859; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. Not which should have accompanied his Revises of "my Reader's Lecture" did not. Asks him to visit and dine.
    See: (Sir Richard Owen Papers. )
  - Letter to "Dear Warren", June 23, 1859; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [E. L.] Layard, London, July 26-27, 1859; 8x5; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Owen papers.) Concerning the establishment of an aquarium. Zoology. Asks for shipment of sherry. Formerly B Ow2.13
  - Letter to ----., August 30, 1859; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Richard] Owen, Jan. 25, 1860; Murchison, Roderick Impey, Sir, 1792-1871
  - Letter to [William] Buckland, Nov. 5, 1860; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "Dear Maria;", April 16, 1861; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Owen Papers.) Friendly letter. Lectures at the Royal Institution Friday night. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to [Sir Roderick Impey] Murchison, May 25, 1861; 6-1/4x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 4p.,end. Cites Du Chaillu in the Proceedings of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia.
  - Letter to [Charles R. Darwin], June 12, 1861; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Owen papers.) Concerning proof for publication. Formerly B Ow2.14 no. 253
  - Letter to John Gould, June 26, 1861; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Lady Cust, Oct. 1, 1861; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Sir E. Ray] Lankester, Oct. 28, 1861; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "My dear Madam", Dec. 6, 1861; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    British Museum, A.L.S. 3p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 27.) Cannot give them a lecture. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to Messrs. Williams & Norgate, Jan. 7, 1862; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "My Lord Duke", Feb. 17, 1862; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Mr. Longman, March 19, 1862; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Sir Austen Henry] Layard, May 5, 1862; 7x4½; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 4p. Relates his effrots to help Layard's brother obtain an appointment. Mentions Sir George Grey.
  - Disraeli's speech on economy., May 19, 1862; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "My dear Friend", May 21, 1862; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 5p. Has read his interesting lecture on the cuckoo. Owen just gave a lecture on the bowerbird of Australia. Owen expresses his appreciation for giving him the information that "led to so welcome a change as that from Kew to this sweet spot."
  - Letter to ----, June 4, 1862; 7" x 4 1/2"; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    British Museum, A.L.S. 3p. Discovery and comments on pair of stag's antlers.
  - Letter to ----, Nov. 7, 1862; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 4p. Lists speaking engagements and discusses where he is to be. Then, perhaps they can get together and talk.
  - Letter to Mr. O'Callaghan, Nov. 10, 1862; 7" x 4 1/2"; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    British Museum, A.L.S. 2p. Requests information on a certain institution. Acquired with the author's On the extent...of a national museum of natural history (507.42: Ow20.2).
  - Letter to [Sir Austen Henry] Layard, Jan. 26, 1863; 7¼x4½; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    British Museum, A.L.S. 4p., end. Has received a letter from Layard's brother, which "foreshows all the usefulness which his comparatively independent position will enable him to manifest towards Natural History, both there [Cape Town] & here".
  - Letter to G[eorg] Forchhammer, June 26, 1863; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "My dear Sir", Nov. 23, 1863; 7x4½; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. Suggests to his correspondent that "it would be instructive to add a Cut of the structure of the serpent's skull..."
  - Letter to Meyer, Dec. 8, 1863; 10-1/2x8; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    London, A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Sir R.Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 5.) Thanks for the publication. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to ----., March 9, 1864; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Charles Buxton], April 29, 1864; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir R.Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 6.) Accepts invitation. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to William White Cooper, July 4, 1864; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 1p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 28.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to "My dear Sir", September 8, 1864; 7-1/4x4-3/4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 3p. Concerning the horns of various animals including cattle, goats and deer.
  - Letter to "My dear Conybeare", Sept. 30, 1864; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "Dear Sir", Nov. 15, 1864; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir R. Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 7.) Friendly letter. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to Mr. Breswell, Feb. 3, 1865; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [William] Sharpey, March 8, 1865; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Owen papers.) Thinks he has been misrepresented in an Abstract published in the Royal Society Proceedings. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to Mrs. Denman, May 23, 1865; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Owen papers.) Thanks for her specimens of natural history of Panama. Concerning Indians skinning the sea otter. Formerly B Ow2.18
  - Letter to Mrs. Arthur Severn, June 22, 1865; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Ed[ward] Wimmer, Nov. 6, 1865; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 29.) Makes a request. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to [Lady] Mary [Cooper], Feb. 1, 1866; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. (see R.Owen Letters to various persons, no. 20.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to [Sir James] Paget, April 20, 1866; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "My dear Madam", May 10, 1866; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 3p.and end. (see Sir R.Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 8.) Concerning fossils. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to "My dear Warren", August 20, 1866; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Thomas Campbell] Eyton, May 8, 1867; 7x4½; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. Informs Eyton that "Prof: Huxley's paper is not out yet." Refers to Cuvier; mentions the dodo.
  - Letter to ----., August 5, 1867; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Sir Edward] Sabine, Nov. 27, 1867; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Sir Austen Henry] Layard, January 8, 1868; 7¼x4½; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    British Museum, A.L.S. 2p. Has transferred the speciman given by Layard's brother to the bird department of the British Museum. Praises E. L. Layard's Birds of South Africa as "an admirable work".
  - Letter to O'Callaghan, Jan. 23, 1868; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 3p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 30.) Will give a talk on birds. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to Beresford Hope, August 13, 1868; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Lady] Mary [Cooper], Dec. 13, 1868; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 31.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to Mr. Pollock, July 2, 1869; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "My dear Sir", Nov. 25, 1869; 7x4½; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. "I regret, on your acct., that I am not a Fellow of the Geographical Soc....[I] am not entitled to recommend for the Fellowship."
  - Letter to [William Fothergill] Cooke, April 6, 1870; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir R.Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 9.) Friendly letter. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to Mr. Cooke, May 17, 1870; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [J. T. Simon], Sept. 2, 1870; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Mr. Pennell, Feb. 11, 1871; 7x4½; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 3p. States that "No seal has two skins; but some have two kinds of hair growing from the same skin". Describes the difference between "hair seals" and "fur seals".
  - Letter to Prof. Turner, Feb. 25, 1871; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "My Dear Frank", May 11, 1871; 7x4 1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    British Museum, A.L.S. 1p. Asks a favor.
  - Letter to R[ichard] H[engist] Horne, Sept. 4, 1871; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Ashley] La Touche, Oct. 7, 1871; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 3p.and end. (see Richard Owen papers.) Comments on powers of observation in people and wants a bone from the "sea-serpent." Formerly B Ow2.9
  - Letter to [William] Longman, Oct. 21, 1871; 6x3-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir R. Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 10.) Friendly letter. Refers to Frazer. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - The fate of the Jardin d'Acclimatation during the late Sieges of Paris., [1871]; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892